<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>didjfin.no</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on didjfin.no</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Premier League fixture difficulty</title>
      <link>/blog/fpl/visualizing-fixture-difficulty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fpl/visualizing-fixture-difficulty/</guid>
      <description>Getting data on upcoming fixtures Visualizing the data Easy heatmap with ggplot2 Interactive heatmap with plotly Even more interactive heatmap with plotly + shiny     When playing Fantasy Premier League, people are very preoccupied with what opposition the players on their team will be facing in the short term. A commonly held belief is that players tend to get more fantasy points against weaker opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dataset for Fantasy Premier League analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/fpl/fantasy-premier-league-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fpl/fantasy-premier-league-data/</guid>
      <description>The Fantasy Premier League API API data from previous seasons Combining data from current and previous seasons    People often ask me if I have some sort of artificially intelligent algorithm assisting me with my Fantasy Premier League (FPL) team. Not because I’m particularly good at FPL, but because my day job is to develop data driven solutions to business problems. The answer has always been ‘no’, but the tone within one of my fantasy leagues has become rather sassy as of late, so I figured it’s time to smash out some data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This website is built using the Hugo framework (borrowing heavily from the Minimal theme), and the excellent blogdown package for R. Hugo websites are static by design, the interactive data visualizations are implemented through a separate Shiny server.   Didrik J. Finnøy
Bergen, Norway
djfinnoy@protonmail.com
  
Work  Data Scientist @ Atea
May 2018 -
 Data analysis Machine learning Programming  Advisor @ NSD - Norwegian Center for Research Data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>